Jai-Hua (Kevin) Yen

0923-550-217 | jaihuayen@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/jai-hua-yen-ba455990/

I am a highly-motivated, fast-learning, and innovative professional that specialized and have a high interest in data science with one-year experience in industry, and two-year experience in academics. I am currently an AI Algorithm Engineer in TutorABC, where I integrate my skills in AI and statistics to give deeper inference in different prospective on business data.

Professional Experience

TutorABC, Taipei, Taiwan

2020 - Now

Al Algorithm Engineer

2020 - Now

- Establish a refund detection model to lower the refund rate by implementing feature extraction of customer's behavior on classes and services, and choosing the best model by evaluating the F1-Score from each trained model (Adaboost, Random Forest, Neural Network)
- Apply computer vision (yolov3) to consumer's responses and company services (OCR) to improve user experience
- Build recommendation system by Bert, FastAPI, and Docker and use it as the response of Line chatbot for customer service
- Implement nature language processing techniques (TFIDF & Bert) to improve the quality of the matching system between our customers and products by performing classification (k-means) of the contents of our educational materials.
- Construct R Shiny Server and JupyterHub by Docker for producing interactive dashboards for stakeholders and BI tool for data analytics usage

Data Analyst 2021 - Now

- Design products based on the information of grouped customer features using factor analysis
- Build interactive dashboards and give data insights to each stakeholder's interested KPI based on statistical analysis and machine learning techniques

National Taiwan University, Taipei, Taiwan

2017 - 2019

Teaching Assistant

- Teach lab courses of introducing programming languages includes: R and EXCEL
- Assist teacher in teaching statistics and linear algebra courses, and correction of homework and examination papers
- Evaluated as the top 10% teaching assistants in National Taiwan University and received the National Taiwan University
 Excellent Teaching Assistant Award

Education

National Taiwan University, Taipei, Taiwan

2017 - 2019

Master of Science in Biometry and Bioinformatics

National Tsing Hua University, Taipei, Taiwan

2013 - 2017

Bachelor of Science in Quantitative Finance

<u>Skills</u>

Software/Tools: Linux, Docker, Git, Tableau, Metabase, Excel (Vlookup)

Programming Languages: R, Python (Keras, Tensorflow), MS-SQL, MY-SQL, MATLAB, SAS, C++

Languages: Mandarin (Native Speaker), English (TOEIC: 910)

Publication

Yen, J.-H., Chiu, C.-H. (2020). Richness estimation with species identity error. *Proceedings 62th International Statistical Institute (ISI) World Statistics Congress*, **Volume 6**, 401-408.